this is a video it's about Azure so we'll be creating a resource group in this
video what is a resource group according to Microsoft a resource group is a
container that holds related resources for an Azure solution the resource group
can include all the resources for the solution or only those resources that you
want to manage as a group so let's say for example let me just break this down
so let's say for example you want to deploy a virtual machine it definitely if
you are trying to deploy a virtual machine you be requested to place a virtual
machine in a resource group so your virtual machine is actually a resource and
also we have the virtual network so the virtual network if you are also trying
to create a virtual machine definitely your virtual your virtual machine
would need an IP address so and again you need to actually create a
resource if your virtual network of course you can place a virtual network in a
same resource group so your virtual network is also a resource so let's try to
create a resource group and now we can have a resource group and then click
create by clicking create you can see your subscription if you have
different subscription subscription you can't really select the rest of
subscription and then you can see the resource group name for example you want to
make sure you give the resource group the right name because sometimes if you
work with all our engineers looking at the name of the resource group can tell
them exactly what does what does what the resource group contains so let me
just say I'm gonna make sure this is gonna be a resource group I'm just gonna
call it rg and I want to install deploy Windows 11 but this is just for a test
environment and I'm gonna call this 001 and then for the region I want to
select West Europe because I live in Europe here we can click nest and then
we can add some tag to this which is causing about tag in a different video so
let's just review and then create so there are no error message we cannot
click create so our resource group has been created so it says let's go to our
resource group at this moment you can see we don't have any resource group any
resource is in our resource group so in the next video I'll be showing how to
create a virtual network which will be placed in this resource group